Santhosh Kumar

Lead Engineer

Accomplished Lead Developer with 9+ years of experience leading projects by acting as architect, developer and programmer analyst. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. Strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

Contact

Address

Chennai, India 600059

Phone

962 071 0151

E-mail

vsk.santhu@gmail.com

Skills

HTML	
MYSQL	
Java\$cript	••••
JQuery	
PHP	•
ReactJS	
Linux	•
Shell Script	•
CSS	
SASS	
Typescript	
Material UI	•
Redux	

Work History

2023-03 -Current

Senior Software Developer L4

Saama Technologies Pvt Ltd.

- In Saama Technologies, Have been working into bio-medical application which holds lot of security standards.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.
- Pioneered new methods of code review to incorporate wider range of voices.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs, and improving functionality.
- Developed user interfaces for deployment on Amazon Web Services (AWS) platforms.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies.
- Coded using HTML, CSS, MUI,React JS,Redux, PostgreSQL and Node JS to develop features for Application.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Worked different stations to provide optimal coverage and meet production goals

2022-07 -2023-02

Senior Front End Developer

Upskillist India Private Limited

 Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.

Software

BootStrap

Advanced

Npm

Upper intermediate

Autotask Upper

intermediate

Jira / BigBucket Advanced

React Js Advanced

Git

Yii Framework ■■■■■

2.0 Advanced

UIVision Advanced

UIPath

Advanced

Advanced

GITHUB

Advanced

Gatsby

Framework

Upper intermediate

- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments.
- Established open and professional relationships with team members to achieve quick resolutions for various issues.
- Worked on product where i used React js, Gatsby Framework, Typescript, AWS S3 and Sass.
- Application Link https://www.upskillist.pro/

2016-02 - Senior Developer 2022-07 Chapter Information of But

Checksum Infosoft Pvt Ltd

- Evaluated and improved development work of other developers on team, working to provide training, constructive criticism and knowledge transfer.
- Responsible for understanding the Business requirements and converting Business Requirements in to Technical Design & Implementation
- Designed and developed forward-thinking systems that meet user needs and improve productivity
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans
- Provided website maintenance and enhancements
- Worked on RPA Tools like UIVision and UIPath for performing automated testing in our software application.
- Integrated with third party API's to my application like Autotask PSA and MSR API's.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and fast-paced atmosphere
- Led Technium project with 10 -person team

2013-12 -2016-01

Associate Software Engineer

Nichehands Technologies Pvt Ltd.

- Involved in requirements specification, workflows of product and software development.
- Used PHP, Yii Frameworks, Javascript, SQL and HTML to develop app-solutions.
- Also involved in performing demos for various customers.
- Developed and implemented completely new social career connectivity web application for users to transform human life in right direction.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in development of E- Commerce application through software life-cycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Built real time Hotel booking application that manages Online ordering, Employee management and handles 10k customers per hour.
- Developed and enhanced customer-facing web applications using Yii2 framework on web-logic.
- These applications included customer account maintenance site as well as shopping cart application to attract new customers. Checked configuration files and logs to uncover root causes of problems.

Education

2009-08 - | 2013-06

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Mahendra Institute of Technology - Namakkal

- Elected to Student Associate for Mahendra Institutions in 2012.
- Elected to Chairman of B.Tech Information
 Technology Department for 2012-2013.

2008-05 - Higher Secondary : Computer

2009-05	Science
2007-03	JUICH

Holy Cross Matriculation Higher Secondary

School - Salem, Tamil Nadu

Completed my 12 standard with 70%

2006-06 - Matriculation

2007-05

Holy Cross Matriculation Higher Secondary

School - Salem, Tamil Nadu

Completed my 10th standard with 70%

Accomplishments

- Developed RPA Tool, resulting in a 50% increase in testing productivity.
- Served as Lead Programmer on Technium.
- Dec 2015, On being Awarded "Best

Customer Satisfaction Award"

at the Annual Awards Ceremony

#Nichehands

Technologies Pvt. Ltd

Certifications

2024-01 "Generative AI for Beginners" from Udemy

2011-11 .NET and Oracle certified professional with 80%